Finding Aid for the Colman Andrews Papers LSC.1428
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Writings by Colman Andrews
  - Stories/screenplays
    - Who wants yesterday's yogi?, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Hallelujah anyway! for Kenneth Patchen, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - To remain what we are, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
      An historical sketch of the Grand Duchy of Luxembourg
    - Tender is the night, or an American tragedy, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Ask Dr. Foolgood, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Andrew Guest, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Old man singing of heroes (The), undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Air-conditioners (The), undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Fuck song (The), undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Broken flight (The), undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Untitled prologue, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Bisevo, ca. 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Great grk adventure (The) - a cautionary tale, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - God is my draft counselor, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Uncle Tom's carbine, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Night I met the Beatles and the night I met De Gaulle (The), undated (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Wedgewood lost (The), undated (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - R+B - different town/father black, undated (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Flowers and romance, undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Legacy, undated (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - I who care, undated (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Human destiny by Lecomte du Nouy, 1965 August 5 (Box 22, Folder 24)
      Polemic by Colman Robert Andrews (A)
    - Wild game dinner, undated (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Sketch for an abstract of an outline of a synopsis for the good guys, undated (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - All right, Peter Gardiner, if you're the father of the pop film then who's the mother?, undated (Box 22, Folder 27)
      Final draft
    - Jogger's tale (The)/Jolt while jogging (A), undated (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Story of a life (The), undated (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Jimini promotion film, undated (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Instrument, undated (Box 22, Folder 31)
      Entry from the virgin dictionary, a work in progress (An)
    - Traffic, undated (Box 22, Folder 32)
      Uncorrected copy
    - Richard Brooks and Looking for Mr. Goodbar, undated (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Flower game, undated (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Carradine/"Bound for Glory", November 8 (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Miss Victory, undated (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - How the leper got his stripes, undated (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Man from Konigsberg, undated (Box 22, Folder 38)
      Musical extravaganza based on the life of Immanuel Kant, such as it was (A)
    - Art film, undated (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Bastard (The), ca. 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - Gathering of thieves, or crime doesn't pay, hardly (A), undated (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Street, undated (Box 22, Folder 42)
      Summary and presentation for the screen
    - Renaissance gang (The), undated (Box 22, Folder 43)
      Presentation for the screen (A)
    - Chloe, undated (Box 22, Folder 44)
      Screen treatment (synopsis)
    - Another Saturday, ca. 1963 (Box 22, Folder 45)
      Outline for the screen (An)
    - XPO '70, undated (Box 22, Folder 46)
      Entertainment for the stage (An)
    - Marquis (The), undated (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Messages, undated (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Trial by reason, undated (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - Captain American, undated (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Great supermarket pick-up (The), undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Thumbs up, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Neoterica, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Theatre review
    - Night of the dunce, undated (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Travel
    - Most beautiful hotel room in the world (The), undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Venice, California, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Los Angeles profile -- Introduction, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Paris -- St. Julien Le Pauvre, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Orvieto (destinations), undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Villa Villoresi -- revised, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Ile St. Louis (The), undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Other Venice (The), undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - San Francisco, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Pike Place market, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
      First page missing
    - Confessions of a Francophile, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - New year's eve in Rome, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - American private enterprise aids government by torture, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Greek government
    - Gardena photo day, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Vancouver Chinatown, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Do you know the way to San Jose?, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Monterey, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Maco travel, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Money for travel, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Majorca, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - La residencia -- revised, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Stapleford park, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Both sides now (Berlin), undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Kona village, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - La gazelle d'or, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Langdon Hall, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Day (and a night) in the life of Barcelona (A) -- revised, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Wine
    - Wine column, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Wine & spirits column, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Wine & spirits column, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
      A-K
    - Wine & spirits column, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
      L-Z
    - Future trends in wine, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Best restaurant wine lists in town (The), undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Bordeaux restaurants, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - New York wine country restaurants, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Lanuedoc-Roussillon (The): French wine's biggest secret -- revised, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Bordeaux -- revised, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Sparkling wines, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Napa Valley update, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Chateau de Jau, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Wines of Catalonia (The), undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Restaurant wine lists, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Restaurant wine rules, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Rose, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Chardonnay, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Cognac, etc. in L.A. restaurants, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Pacific northwestern wines, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Edna Valley wines, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Is there anybody down there drinking us? (Oregon wine in California), undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Beaujolais nouveau, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Wine south of San Jose -- revised, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - German wine, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Chateau d'Yquem, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Napa valley (The) - California's wine country, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - California aperitif and dessert wines (sherry, port, etc), undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
      L.A. Magazine, not used
    - Right time of the white (California's 1975 chardonnays) (The), undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Case of great Californians (A), undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Liquidators, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Wine cocktails, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Hangovers, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - How to read a French wine label (sidebar), undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Aperitifs - The bitter and the sweet, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Pinot noir, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Petit sirah, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Royalty of California wine (The), undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Class glass -- 25 great gift bottles, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Current fantasies, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Souse of the border, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Whining on the vines: why the wine biz is hard-pressed, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Hot drinks, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Hotel bars, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Light beers, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Cordials, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Port, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Summer smoothies, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Italian wine, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - California wine notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Secret sippers, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Liquid articles, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Up from cognac, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Port complex (The), undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Wines of the pacific northwest, 1978 October 9 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - House wines, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Armagnac, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Wine, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Willi's Wine Bar, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Wine - magazine clippings
    - Wine notes, 1977 June 27 (Box 8, Folder 34)
      L.A. Magazine, galley 22, 5th proof
    - White plague (The), undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
      Players, vol. 2, no. 2, p. 85-86, 2 copies
    - Boozin' Italian style, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
      Players, vol. 2, no. 3, p. 81-86, 2 copies
    - Vodka, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
      Players, vol. 2, no. 4, p. 75-76, 2 copies
    - California wines, undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
      Players, vol. 2, no. 5, p. 65-68, 75-78
    - Alpine whites, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
      Players, vol. 2, no. 6, p. 81-86, 2 copies
    - Party pluck, undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
      Players, vol. 2, no. 9, p. 79-82, 85-86, 2 copies
    - French ticklers, undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
      Players, vol. 2, no. 10, p. 89-94, 3 copies
    - Holiday drinks, undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
      Players, vol. 3, no. 8, p. 65-68, 82-83
    - Cold foaming fun, undated (Box 8, Folder 43)
      Players, vol. 3, no. 11, p. 68-72
    - Bourbon, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
      Players, p. 85-86